





## **Ashutosh Shrivastava**

ashutoshkarunya@gmail.com |+91-9916200828

CMS specialist with 9 years of experience in executing projects in the areas of Architecture solution and design, development, deployment, and support.

Specialized in Enterprise and Content Management Systems, integrations with complex applications, third party APIs and systems.

Extensive experience in Web Content Management Systems like AEM6.x, CQ5.6 and CQ5.4.

## **Core Competencies**

- Adobe AEM
- Adobe AEM Forms
- Adobe Sign
- Automated Forms Conversion.
- Adobe Designer
- XSD

- XDP
- Estimation
- System Integrations
- Caching Strategy
- Customization OOB components
- Project Setup

- Architecture
- Troubleshooting
- Solution Design
- Dispatcher setup

### **Tools and Technologies**

- **CMS** Adobe AEM (5.4 to 6.5), Adobe AEM forms (6.4 & 6.5)
- **IDE** CRX DE, Adobe Designer, Eclipse
- Backend Java, Python
- **Database** MySQL, SQL Server

- **DevOps** Jenkins , Bitbucket
- **Frontend** JavaScript, jQuery, HTML 5, CSS 3, REST API, JSON, XML
- Multi-Cloud AWS, Azure
- **Source Control** SVN , Git , Tortoise Git

#### **Work experience summary**

Organization	Duration	Designation
Wipro	29th October 2018 - Till Date	Architect
Publicis Sapient	27th October 2014 to 22nd October 2018	Senior Associate Technology L1
Accenture	2 <sup>nd</sup> January 2013 to 20 <sup>th</sup> October 2014	Software Engineering Analyst

#### **Educational Qualification**

Course	Board/University	Year of Passing	Percentage
B.Tech (Electronics and Communication Engineering)	Karunya University Coimbatore	2012	84.8
Higher Secondary	CBSE	2008	81.6
SSLC	CBSE	2006	74.6

# **Project details**

Project	HSBC - DDCS
Role	AEM / AEM Forms Architect
Tool &	AEM 6.5, AEM Forms 6.5, Java
Technology	
Description	AEM forms hosted on internal servers for branch staff to capture users data.
Roles &	POC, project setup, requirement gathering , project estimation and code
Responsibilities	reviews.
	Architecting the entire solution for HSBC which includes AEM forms
	integration.
	Development of framework for backend integration .
	Created a frame work which has increased the efficiency of development by
	80%.

Project	Allied Irish Bank- MCX
Role	AEM Lead Developer
Tool &	AEM 6.4, Java
Technology	
Description	This website is about the Mortgage facility provided by AIB.
Roles &	AEM lead developer along with that worked on designing and estimation.
Responsibilities	Worked on development tasks including UI, AEM and Web Server activity.
	Coordinate with client technical teams and business owners.
	Actively involved in knowledge sharing, mentoring junior team members to
	ensure the software developed adheres to best practices and quality standards
	through code and design reviews.

Project	Sapient Alumni Redesign
Role	AEM Lead Developer
Tool &	AEM 6.3, JAVA
Technology	
Description	This website is for ex-employee of Sapient along with few Admin user. This website is developed using AEM 6.3 version.
Roles &	<ul> <li>Responsible for quality delivery of the project in technical aspects.</li> </ul>
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Responsible for converting business requirement to a technical solution, project design, mentoring the team &amp; high level of tracking for the deliverables</li> <li>Worked on development task including UI, AEM and Web server activity.</li> <li>Created custom Workflow and launcher configurations.</li> <li>Actively involved in knowledge sharing, mentoring junior team members to</li> </ul>
	Actively involved in knowledge sharing, mentoring junior team members to ensure the software developed adheres to best practices and quality standards through code and design reviews.

Project	Illinois State Lottery
Role	AEM Lead Developer
Tool &	AEM 6.1, JAVA
Technology	
Description	The Illinois State Lottery (known simply as the Illinois Lottery) is an American lottery for the U.S. state of Illinois, currently operated by Camelot Illinois from January 2018; previously Northstar Illinois group operated it. This is a promotional website with list of games, rules and winning number details. This was developed in AEM 5.6.1 and then migrated to AEM 6.0 and AEM 6.1 version.
Roles &	Production Support and handle any issues reported.
Responsibilities	Production deployment of new games on monthly basis.
	Completed technical transition from business owner Northstar Illinois group
	to Camelot Illinois.

Project	The Community
Role	AEM Lead Developer
Tool &	AEM 6.1, Java
Technology	
Description	The community / la comunidad is an innovative, cross-cultural, global creative marketing and Advertising agency.
	marketing and Advertising agency.
Roles &	Worked on project setup, requirement gathering and project estimation.
Responsibilities	Worked on end-to-end livefyre social integration for website.
	• Involved in the end-to-end implementation phase for website from QA to
	Production.
	Code base handling and Project document management in confluence.

Project	Sapient Corporation
Role	AEM Lead Developer
Tool & Technology	AEM 6.1, Java
Description	<b>Publicis.Sapient</b> is a marketing and consulting company that provides business, marketing, and technology services to clients. The company operates three divisions, SapientRazorfish formerly known as Sapient Nitro, Sapient Global Markets and Sapient Government Services.
Roles & Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Was involved in the Second phase of website development for Sapient Government Services site.</li> <li>Involved in end-to-end development and implementation of Publicis sapient site redesign.</li> <li>Code base handling and Project document management in confluence.</li> </ul>

Project	Lord, Abbett & Co. LLC Redesign, Migration and Support.
Role	AEM Developer
Tool & Technology	AEM 6.0, Java
Description	<b>Lord, Abbett &amp; Co.</b> LL is an independent, privately held investment manager headquartered in Jersey City, New Jersey. The firm offers a variety of fixed-income and equity strategies to individual and institutional investors. This was developed in AEM 5.6.1 and then migrated to AEM 6.0C
Roles & Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Worked on redesign and migration track from AEM 5.6.1 to AEM 6.0</li> <li>Worked on major functionality like Daily data, Monthly Data feed for LA.</li> <li>Responsible for all build and release for Lord Abbett support track.</li> <li>Involved in Bug fixing and providing solutions to CR's.</li> <li>Third party integration development of LDAP and DST Vision.</li> <li>Worked with a technical architect on complete deployment and cutover process for upgrade track from old server to new server.</li> </ul>

Project	Henkel
Role	AEM Developer
Tool & Technology	Adobe CQ 5.6.1, Java
Description	Henkel AG & Company, KGaA, is a German chemical and consumer goods company headquartered in Düsseldorf, Germany. It is active in both the consumer and industrial sector, organized into three globally operating business units (laundry & home care, beauty care, adhesive technologies).
Roles & Responsibilities	Responsible for maintenance and enhancement of existing website.

Project	Coca-Cola Journey
Role	AEM Developer
Tool &	Adobe CQ 5.6.1, Java
Technology	
Description	Coca-Cola Journey is a digital magazine that focuses on important topics, social causes and news about The Coca-Cola Company.
Roles & Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Worked on reusable components and templates.</li> <li>Worked on Facebook social media integration.</li> <li>Involved in all stages of the project starting from requirement gathering to website go live.</li> </ul>

Project	National Bank of Canada
Role	AEM Developer
Tool &	Adobe CQ 5.6.1 , Java
Technology	
Description	The National Bank of Canada is the sixth largest commercial bank in Canada. It has headquartered in Montreal, and has branches in most Canadian provinces and 2.4 million personal clients.
Roles & Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Participated in analysis and requirement gathering.</li> <li>Worked on reusable components and templates.</li> </ul>

#### **Certification**

### **Adobe Experience Manager**

- 1. Adobe Experience Manager Sites Business Practitioner
- 2. Adobe Experience Manager Sites Developer
- 3. Adobe Experience Manager Sites Architect
- 4. Adobe Experience Manager Forms Developer

### **Cloud Technology**

- 1. AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (Validation Number 70E91S01PBRE1MKY)
- 2. Microsoft Azure Fundamentals (Certification Number H423-8657)

## **Awards and recognition**

- 1. Top Talent Award from Wipro Digital for Qualifying AMCAT Exam.
- 2. Outstanding Contribution to AIB-Wipro 2019.
- 3. Supernova Award for Sapient Corporation Project in 2018.
- 4. Star of the Account for Henkel Project in 2015.
- 5. Certificate of Merit and scholarship by Eastern Railway Women's Welfare Organization in 2008 for outstanding performance in Higher Secondary Examination.

#### Personal Profile

Father's Name	Sachida Nand Sinha
Date of Birth	10 April 1991
Languages Known	English, Hindi
Interests	Fishkeeping, Aquascaping, Football.
Nationality	Indian

Place: Bangalore Ashutosh Shrivastava

Date: \ \